Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Warp complete.
Error correction, 20, 15, 10.
Correction data sent.
Prepare to fire the transit wave motion gun.
Target scope, open.
Targeting the core of the comet.
Open the circuit to the wave motion gun.
Opening the circuit to the wave motion gun.
Close all emergency valves.
CRS booster connected.
Neu Deusular is warping out
at the planned coordinates.
Energy charge, 120%.
Ten seconds to fire.
All hands, prepare for shock and flash.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
My Neu Deusular will protect the Yamato from the radiant energy from the transit wave motion gun…
Six.
Two.
One.
Transit wave motion gun, firing !
H…how…
More powerful than the wave motion gun…?!
A strange fate.
The ship guided by Teresa...
...is the Yamato.
Incoming message from Zoellgute !
Attention Yamato, the Garmillas forces will use their full
strength to escort you to the center of the imperial capital.
Leave the defense of Earth to us.
Ambassador Barrel…
We share the same operational objectives.
The destination is the Emperor's throne room.
You can't warp into there,
but with our technology…
A dimensional submarine has appeared.
This is a first attempt.
Even with four special ships,
we can only escort the Yamato.
And we still have no guarantee of success.
This must also be fate.
Let the dimensional submarines guide us.
Synchronize all ships, then rapid dive !
Rapid dive !
Hold the line until the Yamato
completes its objective...
...no matter what !
Approaching the break-out point.
This is as far as we go.
It's all up to you, Yamato.
See you again.
Right in the middle of enemy territory ?
Keep a sharp eye out.
Unknown heat sources, detected.
Karakrum class vessels, but they're small.
They vary in size.
That's…
Just like Katsuragi Touko's information,
this is where Gatlantis's ships are built.
Link each system to
the auto-navigation system !
That light…
Diversion through cosmo wave…
We can't block it because it's
our highest clearance level.
She's also a Silver Maiden.
She's capable of controlling
the Comet Empire's capital.
The gate…
The gate's been closed for
the last thousand years, but…
Sabera…!
A doll is no match, huh ?
Lazera !
My lord !
Show it to me.
System hacking, successful.
All hands, the ship will enter
the center of the enemy base !
Space cavalry, move out !
All space fighters, take off !
No, it's not accepting my command…
What's wrong ?!
Ship's stern hit !
Starboard aft, it's the engine room !
Captain !
Go.
Damage report.
At this rate, the ship won't…
Zorder knows that Golem is our target.
Do or die…
We all knew that from the start.
Break through the middle.
Severe damage to the engine !
Closing all partitions !
Begin emergency maneuvers !
Turn off all unnecessary power !
Doctor, the sickbay is full !
Lay him down in the corridor !
You know triage, right ?!
Yes !
Save as many as possible !
Teresa, can you hear me ?
Teresa…
I don't remember Telezart.
But I feel like I know it.
If you're there, tell me if there's
any meaning to this suffering.
Do our lives have any meaning
that's worth this bloodshed ?
I can't control the engine output,
but the ship can maintain speed.
Chief Engineer Tokugawa...?!
Chief !
We're born alone, and die alone.
Why do people meet ?
Watch out !
Analyzer !
Doctor !
Let me go !
He's not just a machine !
There's no replacement !
Doc...tor…
...thank you…
We've lost so much.
Family, friends...
...and even memories with loved ones.
I don't want to lose any more.
Captain !
Please don't take anymore away !
Please hold on !
Get Doctor Sado !
No need.
Remain calm.
Look at them.
They're still under Katsuragi Touko's control.
Utilize the Yamato's system
to make use of them.
Asteroid ring…
Let it protect our aerial forces,
then break through the gate.
You can do it, can't you ?
Yes, sir.
Kodai...
...you are the next captain.
Grab the future with your hands.
Future…
Let's carry out former
Captain Hijikata's orders !
The magnetron wave is synchronized
with Touko's cosmo wave.
This is Kodai.
I'm joining the aerial force, and entering
the gate with the advance unit.
Alright !
Enemy ahead !
What's that ?
I'll take care of this,
so you guys go ahead !
Thanks.
I won't run.
Now I want to live so badly.
I want to see Makoto's face.
I want to carry Tsubasa on my shoulders.
I want to do the things I couldn't do before !
I'll return home alive, no matter what !
How pathetic of me...
But Dad won't give up until the end !
Do you know, Tsubasa ?
Your dad is really cool.
I'm closing the gate.
Maximum thrust !
Kodai, I'll take care of them.
Keyman…
Opening the Gates of Lerte.
I'll guide you to Golem.
Oh no, they're almost here.
Sabera, you should be able to hear me.
Don't close your mind !
Why do you reject me ?
You know better than anyone
how vain humans are.
You even reactivated the Ark of Destruction.
So why this ?
I shouldn't have reactivated it !
Why ?
Mill…
Our son was killed twice.
Right.
You have a heart, which enables
you to feel sadness and despair.
Heart ?
You're human...
...more than anyone.
There you are.
Hurry, the gates are…!
Dammit !
Splendid.
I commend you for making it this far.
However, I'm curious about your next move.
You no longer have the
protection of that woman.
Touko…?!
Why ?!
She's your…
You of all people ask why ?!
You sacrificed her and so
many others to come here !
You said you wouldn't pull the trigger.
Meet your doom, humans.
Kodai !
Right.
Commander ?
Sorry I'm late !
Seize Golem ! Hurry !
Your Majesty, please withdraw for now.
Are you going to claim victory ?
If you're humans, we should
be able to talk this out.
Human, you say ?
Your future self has taught me.
That "future"...
...has died.
There's no end, as always.
Watch out !
You're safe…
I admit…
Zorder…
We are also human.
Wait !
Episode 24
Yamato, Seize the Comet Empire!
Sotto oyasuminasai
A gentle goodnight
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Analyzer:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Sado Sakezo:
Saijo Miki:
Hirata Hajime:
Kasahara Maki:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Yuki Chiba
Cho
Mugihito
Chiba Shigeru Chiba
Moriya Satomi
Ise Fumihide
Honda Mariko
Osanago no youna toiki
You breathe like a little child
Kato Saburo:
Kato Makoto:
Yamamoto Akira:
Saito Hajime:
Nagakura Shiori:
Kurata Masaru:
Katsuragi Touko:
Hijikata Ryu:
Abelt Desler:
Klaus Keyman:
Lauren Barrel:
Fomt Berger:
Wolf Flaken:
Gol Heini:
Yarve Skelge:
Hosoya Yoshimasa
Sato Rina
Tanaka Rie
Tochi Hiroki
Amagai Kazusa
Yoshikai Kiyohito
Kaida Yuko
Kusumi Naomi
Yamadera Koichi
Kamioya Hiroshi
Terasoma Masaki
Suwabe Junichi
Nakada Joji
Sato Setsuji
Cho
Itsumademo soba ni iru kara
I'll be by your side forever
Zorder:
Gailane:
Sabera:
Geniz:
Lazera:
Tezuka Hideaki
Shibata Hidekatsu
Kaida Yuko
Umetsu Hideyuki
Harasawa Kouki
Mabuta tojite
So close your eyes
Hidamari no takeru youna yasashisa de...
As gentle as warm sunlight...
...Tsusumi komu yo
...I'll embrace you
Shiawase umidasu chikara
The power to bring happiness
Fuwari fuwari fuwa fuwa yume no naka
Drifting and floating, feeling like I'm having a dream
Omoi haseru yorisoinagara
Cuddling up and thinking of you from afar
Itsudemo waratte ite hoshii to negau
My wish is for you to keep on smiling
Never let your childlike smile disappear
Ubu na egao tayasanu youni
Itooshii hito yo...
My dearest one...
Preview
Oh, no. It's spontaneously
consuming the imperial capital…
That's the Ark of Destruction…
The Yamato has sustained
serious damage to the engine...
Crash the Yamato into it, right ?
I don't want
to lose anyone anymore !
Kodai !
Grab the future with your hands.
Episode 25
Farewell, Space Battleship Yamato